enfamil.com 2018-08-17

# Privacy Policy | Enfamil US

Effective Date: June 16, 2015

For Our Customers in the United States

**I. Purpose of This Privacy Policy**  
 **II. Information We Collect**  
 **III. Use and Disclosure of Your Information**  
 **IV. Use of Cookies and Web Beacons; Web Tracking**  
 **V. Opt-Out; Update and Correction of Personal Information**  
 **VI. Security**  
 **VII. California Residents: Your Privacy Rights**  
 **VIII. Exclusions**  
 **IX. Changes in Our Privacy Policy**  
 **X. Contact Us**

Mead Johnson Nutrition respects the privacy of its customers, including visitors to its websites, and understands that information about you, your health, and your health care is sensitive. **Mead Johnson Nutrition will not sell or rent your Personal Information to third parties for their own marketing purposes** , except as provided in the “Transfer of Control” subsection of this Privacy Policy. Mead Johnson Nutrition developed this Privacy Policy to provide information about our practices regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of information that you may provide when using the Enfamil website (which includes the Enfamil Online Shop and the Enfamil mobile website) and the Enfamil mobile apps. We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy before submitting information or using this website or the mobile apps. By submitting information or using this website or the mobile apps, you acknowledge that you understand and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, “Personal Information” is data specifically about you, which you typically provide on a voluntary basis. Aggregate or combined information includes data that is related to you but studied as a group and does not identify you specifically. You cannot “opt-out” from having aggregate information collected except as otherwise specified in this Privacy Policy.

**Information You Voluntarily Provide on the Website**

You can visit much of our website without telling us who you are or providing us with other Personal Information. Some areas of our website allow you to contact us to ask questions or provide comments, including via surveys from our service providers. When you communicate with us and request a response, we ask for your name and contact information so that we may respond to you. Some areas of our website may also require that you submit information to access specific content, features, interactive tools, services, or participate in a particular activity. For example, to create an online account for the Enfamil Online Shop or to subscribe to an email newsletter, we may ask for certain Personal Information such as your name, contact information, address, credit card information if you are making a purchase, and perhaps additional information so we can tailor our response to your request. In addition, when you access certain interactive tools or service, you may be asked to provide Personal Information. Other features of the website, such as the profile update feature, may ask you to provide information such as your education level or certain medical information regarding you, your infant, or your child. You may always choose not to provide the requested information, but then you may not be able to participate in the particular activity that requires the information.

**Information You Voluntarily Provide on the Mobile Apps**

Certain features and tools may be developed for the Enfamil mobile apps that may collect certain information from you. If you provide such information for these mobile app-specific tools and features, we will not use such information except to provide you with those tools and features. For example, the Birth Announcement Creator tool may ask you for your baby’s name, time and date of birth, length, weight and photo to create a birth announcement for you. In addition, the mobile apps may provide enable you to choose to share certain information with certain third parties, such as via Facebook or email.

Note that if you visit the Enfamil website on your mobile device (separate from the Enfamil mobile apps), the portions of this Privacy Policy applicable to the website will apply.

**Information We Automatically Collect**

If you use the Enfamil website, we will automatically gather and store certain information about your visit, such as your IP address and your browser type, which is in addition to and separate from any Personal Information that you provide. We may collect this information through the use of cookies, web beacons, and log files. Through our log files, our website keeps track of usage data, such as the source address that a page request is coming from (i.e., your IP address, domain name), date and time of the page request, the referring website (if any), and other parameters in the URL (e.g., search criteria). None of this automatically collected information is deemed to be Personal Information.

**Use and Disclosure of Personal Information**

We use the Personal Information you provide us in connection with the service you request or to otherwise contact you. For example, if you use the Enfamil Online Shop, we may use your Personal Information to process your order from the Enfamil Online Shop, to contact you about your order, and to send you emails relating to your order or shopping cart.

We may personalize and customize our website for certain visitors. From time to time we may ask you to respond to optional survey questions to further personalize your experience as our customer. If you provide information about yourself, you may find the website customized with references to products and/or services that we believe may be of interest to you, based on your previous interactions and information you have provided to us.

If you do provide us with Personal Information, you agree that we may contact you through a variety of means, such as postal mail, telephone, or email, to provide you with information we believe may be of interest to you. You may opt-out of this service as described in the “Opt-Out; Update and Correction of Personal Information” section of this Privacy Policy.

To help provide our services, we occasionally provide information to other companies that work on our behalf. For example, if you enroll in a Mead Johnson Nutrition program, we may also provide your information to our service providers who help Mead Johnson Nutrition develop programs and provide services to you, or for information processing (including analytics), postal mailing, and/or Internet-based delivery purposes. Our service providers may compile and use non-personally identifiable aggregated data to provide the services. We may also share your information with other Mead Johnson Nutrition companies who might invite you to participate in one of their programs.

We may also disclose your Personal Information as necessary (1) if we determine a website or policy violation has occurred, or to enforce the Enfamil Terms of Use; (2) if we believe such disclosure is necessary to identify, contract or bring legal action regarding injury or interference with the rights and property of Mead Johnson Nutrition, including to enforce Mean Johnson Nutrition’s rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to Mean Johnson Nutrition’s information technology assets or against other inappropriate use of the website or mobile apps; (3) to comply with laws, regulations, court orders and subpoenas or similar requests for information by authorities, or as otherwise required by law (including as described in the “Regulatory Requirements” subsection below); (4) to protect your safety and the safety of others; and (5) to assist us in fraud prevention or investigation. If we are required to divulge Personal Information to law enforcement agencies, we will take appropriate measures to ensure that the requester understands the sensitive nature of any health-related Personal Information they may receive.

Mead Johnson Nutrition will not sell or rent your Personal Information to third parties for their own marketing purposes, except as provided in the “Transfer of Control” subsection below.

**Use and Disclosure of Non-Personal Information**

We use information we automatically collect (e.g., through log files and cookies) to better understand website usage on the whole, to determine which areas of our websites users prefer (e.g., based on the number of visits to those areas), to improve the utility of the material available on the website, and for other statistical reporting and analysis or other purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

Our website may make use of location-based features to customize offers and content based on your geographic location. To deliver these features we will collect information about your IP address via geo-filtering service. By using this website, you consent to the collection and use of your website location data for purposes of delivering these location-based features.

Mead Johnson Nutrition may also share aggregated or de-identified information and automatically collected information that it collects from its various users and share it with our business partners and other third parties.

**Use and Disclosure of Feedback**

Mead Johnson Nutrition will not treat as confidential any information that you provide that is not Personal Information, such as questions, comments, ideas, or suggestions. By submitting content to the Mead Johnson Nutrition website, you automatically grant Mead Johnson Nutrition, or warrant that the owner of such content has expressly granted Mead Johnson Nutrition, the license described in the Enfamil Terms of Use. You should be aware that Mead Johnson Nutrition will be free to disclose, including to our service providers, business partners and advertising providers, through any reasonable means and use for any marketing, internal research, or customer service purposes, such information in its sole discretion. By providing such information to Mead Johnson Nutrition, you understand and agree that no relationship has been created between Mead Johnson Nutrition and you, and Mead Johnson Nutrition has no obligation to you whatsoever regarding that information.

**Transfer of Control**

Circumstances may arise where we decide to reorganize or divest part or all of our business or a line of our business, including our information databases and websites, through a sale, divestiture, merger, acquisition, or other means of transfer. In any such circumstance, Personal Information may be shared with, sold, transferred, rented, licensed or otherwise provided or made available by us or on our behalf to actual or potential parties to, and in connection with, the contemplated transaction (without any further notice to you).

**Use of Offline Information**

Mead Johnson Nutrition may combine Personal Information provided offline with online information as well as records obtained by third parties. This consolidation of information allows us to communicate with you more effectively. Such combined information will be used, shared, and disclosed in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Regulatory Requirements**

If you contact us regarding your experience with using any of our products, we may use the information you provide in submitting reports to the U.S. Food and Drug Administration, and as otherwise required of us by law or governmental audit. We may also use the information to contact your healthcare professional to follow up regarding an unexpected event involving the use of any one of our products. You understand that to comply with the law, Mead Johnson Nutrition may not be permitted to comply with your request to amend or remove Personal Information that was provided to Mead Johnson Nutrition by a healthcare professional or a consumer regarding an adverse event or reaction involving medicine or medical devices.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

We store some information on your computer using a technique your browser supports called “cookies.” The cookies are used for a variety of purposes, including but not limited to: helping you sign in (e.g., remembering your user ID if you enroll or register), remembering some of your customized user preferences (if elected), and helping us better understand how people use our websites. In some cases, this information will help us tailor content to your interests or help us avoid asking for the same information when you revisit our websites. To disable or limit the use of cookies, please refer to the options provided by your Internet browser. If you do so, however, some pages on our websites may not work properly.

We also allow third-party companies, including AddThis and those described in the “Web Tracking” subsection below, to collect certain information when you visit our website. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information during your visits to this and other websites to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or a third party web beacon to collect this information. A web beacon is a clear image or pixel tag in Graphics Interchange Format (GIF) that we (as well as other companies) place on pages of our website to allow Internet advertising or audience measurement companies to help us analyze our advertising campaigns and general usage patterns of visitors to our websites.

If you prefer that we do not collect non-personally identifiable information about your website visits for the purpose of delivering targeted advertising, you may opt-out by visiting the AddThis website and clicking on the “Opt-Out” button. You can also learn more about this behavioral advertising practice and opt-out of targeted advertising delivered by multiple ad networks at the Network Advertising Initiative.

**Web Tracking**

When you visit our website, our third-party advertising partners and analytics providers (e.g., Google Analytics, KISSmetrics) may collect information about your online activity on the website and on third-party websites. These providers may set web tracking tools (e.g., cookies and web beacons) to collect non-personally identifiable information regarding your online activity. In addition, our advertising partners may use this information to deliver advertisements to you when you visit third-party websites within their networks, as described above. You may opt-out of each analytics service as provided below.

_Google Analytics_

The website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help us analyze how users use the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage (such as page visits, time on site, time on page, etc.). Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser; however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of the website. By using the website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. More information about Google Analytics is available here: <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>. To opt out of the Google Analytics collection of information, visit: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

_KISSmetrics_

The website uses KISSmetrics to obtain analytics information regarding the activities that users engage in while visiting the website. KISSmetrics collects certain information, including via cookies, such as your browser information, IP address, mobile device information, operating system information, time of visit, etc. Please see KISSmetric’s privacy policy here: <https://www.kissmetrics.com/privacy/>. If you would like to opt-out of KISSmetrics tracking, please visit this page: [https://www.kissmetrics.com/user-privacy/](https://www.kissmetrics.com/user-privacy).

**California Do-Not-Track Disclosures**

Certain web browsers may include settings that allow you to provide “do not track” (DNT) signals to the websites you visit. However, DNT is an evolving technology that currently lacks finalized industry protocols and standards. As such, our website does not currently respond to DNT signals.

When we collect Personal Information from you, you may tell us that you do not want it used for further marketing contact and we will respect your wishes. You can update your marketing options via opt-out instructions at the bottom of any email from us or, if you have registered for the website or the Enfamil Online Shop, via the Profile Update feature. Note that opting out of marketing emails will not prevent you from receiving transactional emails (e.g., emails relating to your Enfamil Online Shop order). In addition, Mead Johnson Nutrition may still contact you in the event of a service or safety notification (e.g., a recall notice), regardless of your stated privacy preferences.

Except as limited in the Regulatory Requirements section of this Privacy Policy, you may update, correct your Personal Information or opt-out from our mailings and other services that you may have previously requested, by contacting us through the email address or phone number listed in the Contact Us section of this Privacy Policy. Note that your prior opt-out requests may be overridden if you sign up for any mailings or services again after such request.

Mead Johnson Nutrition is committed to maintaining the protection of the Personal Information you provide us. However, we cannot guarantee that it is completely secure from people who might attempt to evade our security measures or intercept transmissions over the Internet, and we will not be held liable for any lack of security relating to the use of the website or mobile apps by you.

If you are a California resident, you may have the right to request and receive certain information about our disclosure of your Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes, and your choices with respect to such disclosures. Because it is our policy not to share your Personal Information with third parties for their own direct marketing purposes unless you are first given the opportunity to opt-out from such sharing, we are exempt from having to meet this requirement. If you still wish to learn more about our compliance with this requirement, please contact us using the information provided in the “Contact Us” section below.

**Privacy Policies Governing Linked Websites**

As a convenience to our visitors, Mead Johnson Nutrition websites contain links to other websites (including other Mead Johnson Nutrition websites) that may offer useful information. The Privacy Policy described here does not apply to your use of those other websites. Before using any linked website, please review the privacy policy posted on the website to understand how personally identifiable information and online activity data collected through the website is used and protected.

**Online Privacy for Children**

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. We do not seek to, nor do we knowingly, collect Personal Information from children under 13 years old. If a child has provided us with Personal Information, the parent or guardian of that child may contact us as indicated in the Contact Us section of this Privacy Policy to have the information deleted from our records.

**Additional Information for Non-U.S. Residents**

This website and material provided on this website are solely for promoting products, programs, and business operations within the U.S. If you provide Personal Information to Mead Johnson Nutrition (including through the Contact Us section below), it may be transferred to and processed on computers in the U.S. and other countries. Do not provide your Personal Information to Mead Johnson Nutrition if you do not want your Personal Information to be transferred to the United States or to other countries, or if the laws in your country restrict these types of transfers. Your provision of Personal Information to Mead Johnson Nutrition will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Your provision of Personal Information to Mead Johnson Nutrition through this website means that you agree to this Privacy Policy.

Mead Johnson Nutrition may at any time revise this Privacy Policy by updating this posting. If we do, we will note near the top of this page the date that any changes are made and/or when they become effective. Your continued use of the website or mobile apps after such changes indicates your acceptance of such revisions. Therefore, you should periodically visit this page to review the most current Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or other aspects of privacy on our websites, please contact us:  
Mead Johnson Nutrition, Fourth Floor, 2701 Patriot Blvd., Glenview, IL 60026 USA  
1-800-BABY123 (M-F 7 am - 7 pm CST/CDT, S 8 am - 4:30 pm CST/CDT)  
Email: [enfamilresourcecenter@enfamil.com](mailto:enfamilresourcecenter@enfamil.com?subject=Questions%20about%20the%20Enfamil.com%20Privacy%20Policy)

Please read our Enfamil Terms of Use.
